キヤ口ル
Carol.
副社長
Vice-director.
Such bad manners.
行儀が悪いな
I'm so sorry!
すいません 私つたら
夢中になつちやつて…
I just got all caught up in this!
What were you doing?
何を していた
者えていたんです
この物語のこと
I was thinking.
About these stories.
Stories?
物語 ?
はい 1930年のー月に始まつた
あの一連の奇怪な物語のことです
Yes, about that series of mysterious stories that started in November 1930.
There was a time when we were traveling on a train together,
いつか…
お前と列車で
旅をしたことがおったな キヤロル
wasn't there, Carol?
あの時 私がお前に言ったことを
覚えているか?
Do you remember what I told you then?
Ehmm...
ええと‥
うゎぁ 虹だあ
It's a rainbow!
キヤ口ル
え?
Carol.
Concerning that rainbow, without a sliver of doubt,
我々は あの虹に対して
子供の頃から なんの疑いもなく
美しいものだと思っている
we've always considered it to be a beautiful thing.
それは なぜか?
んん‥
Why is that?
Among those who know nothing about the refraction of light,
光の屈折など知らない人々は
are probably also some who think of it as a prelude to a natural disaster.
天変地異の前触れと
思うこともあるだろう
あの虹を伝って 何か良からぬものが
降りてくるかもしれない
Through that rainbow, something bad might descend.
あの虹の根元では 草木が
燃え尽きているかもしれない
The vegetation at the foot of that rainbow might be on fire.
Why do we feel that these rainbows are so fairytale like?
我々は なぜ
あの七色という情報に
メ丿しへンを感じることが
できるのであろうか…
者えてみたことはないか?
Have you ever thought about that?
ないです
I haven't.
I mean, even if you think about it, there's no way to know.
だつて 者えたつて分かり ませんし
それに私たちの仕事は
者えることじやなくて
Besides that, rather than thinking,
it is our job to relay existing information to the people.
すでにある結果を
人に伝えることですから!
3ー 9点
319 points.
え? 何点中蝿
Out of how many points?
Like you said, our job is to relay information to the people.
確かに我々の仕事は
人々に真実を伝えることだ
However, the moment we obtain information, unrelated to whether that information is true or false,
だが情報を手にした瞬間
それが真実であろうと偽りであろうと…
we cannot stop thinking there.
者えることを
やめてはならない
情報の真偽を見極めただけで
終わらせてはならないのさ
We can't stop thinking after determining its authenticity.
それが情報を
人に引き渡す者の責任だ
That is the responsibility of those who hand information over to the people.
But thinking... About what?
でも 者えるつて何を…
者えたからって
真実が変わるわけでも ないですよね?
It's not like the truth will change if we think about it.
いいや 変わるさ
No... It changes.
ゎあ!
思い出したか キヤロル
Do you remember now, Carol?
はい… 副社長
Yes, Vice-director.
A story...
物語‥
それは情報ではなく
情報の蓄積でもない
It's not information, nor is it the accumulation of information.
者えられた結果だ
Its conclusion is predefined.
キャロル お前はなぜ この物語力ヾ
ー930年ーー月に始まると者えたのだ?
Carol, why did you think this story started in November 1930?
ええっと
Ehmm...
What's the matter, Carol?
どうした キヤ 口ル
お前はそれでも
このデイ リ一デイ ズ 副社長
And you call yourself the assistant of Daily Days' Vice-director, Gustave Saint Germain?
ギユス夕一ヴ'サンジ工ルマンの
助手か?
それは…
That is...
For example, Carol...
例えばだ キヤ口ル
それはー 7ー ー 年
It is the year 1711.
大西洋を航行中の
アドウ工ナアウイス号の船内から
It might be a good idea to start from within the ship, Advena Avis,
which was crossing the Atlantic.
始めてもよいかもしれない
It might also be a good idea to start from the tragic event that occurred on
あるいは それは…
大陸横断特急
フライ ング プツシ一フツ 卜号を蓑つた
the transcontinental train, Flying Pussyfoot, and was secretly swept under the rug.
人知れず闇へと葬られた惨劇から…
始めてもよいかもしれない…
にもかかゎらず キヤロル…
Regardless of all that, you have chosen November 1930 as the start of the story.
お前はー930年ーー月を
物語の始まり に選んだ…
So... Why is that?
それは なぜだ?
副社長 それは
Vice-director, that is...
それはですね
That is because I considered the difficulty of its comprehension.
分かりやすさということを
者えたからです
私たちの目に この事件が
飛ぴ込んできたのは
When we caught hint of that story, that was the first thing we came across.
あの時が最初でした
だから…
That's why—
156 points.
ー56点
Eh, out of how many points?
え? 何点中…
It may definitely be easy to understand it that way.
確かに分かりやすくはあるだろう
だがキヤロル
However, Carol...
者えるベきは時間軸だけではない
You shouldn't think only about the chronology.
人物もまたそうだ
Humans are like that as well.
For example...
例えば…
やり
あいてつ !
Ouch!
ゎああ! アイザツク一ツ
Isaac!
あの2人組の風変わりな強盗を
主人公としてみてはどうか
How about we see that peculiar robber duo as the lead characters?
あるいは…
Or...
That boy who suffers from his cursed destiny.
呪われた運命に苦しむ あの少年…
Or...
あるいは…
Gandor family's intelligent executive.
ガンド一丿しファ三リ一の
若き頭脳派幹部…
Or...
あるいは…
そぅいうことなら…
If that's what you mean...
お恵みを お恵みをお与え下さい
Please... Can you please spare some change?
主は あなたの行いを見ておられます
The guardians watch over your actions, and your actions will eventually—
その行いは やがて主の…
Old man.
峯さん
Because he is lead character-ish.
主役つぽいからです
…ぽい?
Ish?
そう… つぽい
Yes, ish.
I'm in a good mood today.
今巳の俺は機嫌がいい
取つときな
Take it.
おおおお!
ありがとうございます 旦那
Thanks so much, Mister!
主もきつと あなたの行いを
祝福して下さいますよ
The guardians shall bless your actions!
都合のいい時だけ信心深くなるのは
やめとけよ 爺さん
Stop playing the devoted believer only when it suits you.
お待ち下さい 旦那
Please wait a bit, Mister!
お礼に今朝方摘んだ花を…
As a thank you, please take some flowers I picked this morning.
They probably withered by now.
どうせ しおれちまつてるだろう?
それはどうですかねえ 旦那アア ア
I wonder about that, Mister!
You don't think so?
じやあ なくなくないですか ?
うう う… アワワ…
ううつ はあ はぁ
なア 教えてくれ
Hey, tell me.
ヒッ… 来るな 化け物
Don't come near me, you monster!
俺をマルテイ一ジヨ'ファ三リ一の
Did you do this knowing that I am Firo Prochainezo from the Martillo family?
フイ一ロプ口シ工ンツオと
知つてのことか 爺さん!
Old man!
ぅおおっ
I see now!
なるほど
主役っぽい
確かにそうかもしれん
Lead character-ish... That may be true...
ですよね?
I thought so!
However, Carol...
だがな キヤ口ル
Depending on who you place in the center of the same accident,
誰を中心に据えるかで
同じ事件は
the characteristics of said accident change kaleidoscopically.
千変万化に姿を変える
In other words, there is one accident,
つまり事件はー つ
however, there are as many stories explaining it,
as many as there are people involved in it.
けれど物語は
それにかかわつた人の数だけあるのだ
Got it, men?!
いいか てめえら
Destroy it all!
何もガもつぶせ !
No need for warnings or negotiation!
警告も交渉も必要ねえ
今は俺たちの時代だ!
Now is our time!
俺たちの世界には
俺たち以外の誰も存在しねぇ !
In our world, no one exists but us!
Whether it's the Gandors or the Martillos destroy them without leaving a trace;
ガンド一ルだろうが
マ丿しテイ一ジヨだろうが
跡形もなく す り つぶして
make it so that it seems as if they never existed in the first place!
完全に その存在を
なかつたことにしてやるんだ!
And?
それで ?
そのアホはどうしたんだ? ラツク
What happened to that idiot, Luck?
チツクさんに任せてあるよ
I'm letting Chic handle it.
野郎 痛みを感じる神経が
残つているか どうか…
Though I'm not sure if the guy has any nerves left to feel pain.
ボス! またやられました!
Boss, we've been done in again!
被害は ?
What's the damage?
賭場と酒場と馬券場が…
A gambling hall, a bar and a betting ticket office...
Luckily, there weren't any casualties.
幸い死人は出ていません
丿しノラ一夕だ!
連中 ぶち飛ばして!
I'm gonna beat, trample and kill those bastards with my own hands!
ぷち倒して!
ぷち殺してくれる!
We've brought one of the guys who got to the bookies.
ー人 馬券場にかち込んできた野郎は
引つ張つてきました
うりやあ てあ一 おりや てめえか!
Was it you?!
The one who attacked our turf?!
うちのシマに
かち込んできたヤロ一つてのはつ !
You're quite spirited.
随分 威勢のいいことだな
うつ う うう…
In other words,
つまり マフィアや力モッラの
抗争劇から始めるってことですか?
You mean to start from the conflict between the mafia or their families?
For example, yes...
ある一例としてな…
ラツクガン ド一ルを眠らせました
We put Luck Gandor to sleep.
There were rumors that he was brilliant,
切れ者の噂でしたが
赤子の手をひねるようなもんです
but it was as easy as taking candy from a baby.
ヒツ ヒツ ハツハツハツハツハ… あ
しよせんガンド一ルなど
ザコ組織です
In the end, the Gandors are just a puny organization.
つぷすのに大した手間は
かからないでしよう
We won't need to go to much trouble to destroy them.
We have made preparations to buy new model taxi bombs from certain sources.
ある筋から新型の特殊爆弾を
購入する手はずもありまして…
いずれはマルテイ一ジヨも
一網打尽に…
Some day we will take care of the Martillos, too—
Rather than that, I need you to do something for me.
それより お前にやってもらわなければ
ならんことがある
Or...
あるいは…
Dallas-niisan...
ダラス兄さん…
どこにいるの?
Where are you?
Or... Carol...
あるいは… キヤロル…
この物語の始まりが
我々であっても
It wouldn't be strange if we were the beginning of this story.
おかしくはないということだよ
まさか
You're kidding.
はつは…
That is Dallas Genoard.
ダラスジ工ノア一ドだ
分かるな
You know him, right?
はぁ ジ工ノア一 ドの次男坊で…
He's Genoard's second son and...
He is the son of Raymond Genoard, whom you killed without informing me,
私の あずかり知らぬところで
お前が勝手に殺した
レイモンドジ工ノア一ドの息子で
ジ工フリ一ジ工ノア一ドの弟の
and he is Jeffrey Genoard's little brother, whom you also killed.
ダラスジ工ノア一ドだ 分かるな
You know what I mean, right?
There's something going on with this Dallas?
はあ そのダラスが何か…
事務所に連絡を入れてきた
I just made a phone call to his office.
He's saying that it was you, Gustavo, who killed his father and brother.
自分の父親と兄を殺したのが
グス夕一ヴオ お前だと言ってる
証拠もあるそうだ
There seems to be evidence as well.
そ そんなはずは
司法関係も買収したはずで…
That can't be...
I'm sure we paid off the justice department and...
証拠なんてあるワケが
There's no way there can be evidence.
Then why does Dallas know your name?
ならばなぜ ダラスから
お前の名が出る?
う それLま‥
That is...
始末をつけろ
Put an end to it.
見つけ出して
ここに連れてこい
Smoke him out and bring him here.
は はい…
Okay. But, what about the Gandors?
しかしガン ド一ルのほうは…
Dallas is your top priority.
ダラスが最優先だ
一刻も早く捜し出せ
Find him as fast as you can.
は はい…
O-Okay...
生かすも殺すも
お任せ頂けますでしょうか
Can I decide whether to let him live or die?
生かすも殺すも ?
Let him live or die?
フン 好きにしろ
Do what you want.
野郎ども ダラスだ
Okay, men!
Dallas!
Find that bloody second son of Genoard's!
憲すしいジ工ノア一ドの次男坊を
見つけ出せ
Dead or alive!
生死は問ゎん !
このグス夕一ヴォ様と
丿しノラ一夕フア三リ一を
We've got to make him pay for making fools out of the Runorata family!
What a pathetic man.
ふ 哀れな男だ
コケにしたツケを
払わせてやるんだ!
Say something!
何か言つてみろ ! あ !
What happened to the guts you had when you attacked our turf?!
うちの績張りを蓑つた度胸は
どうしたつ!
この程度の覚悟は
できてるんだろうがつ !
You must've been prepared for something like this!
げはぁ…
Don't give me that "Gehaah" crap!
げはあじゃねぇんだ! げはあじゃ
あおっ !
何か言おって言つてんだがな! おらヨ !
I'm telling you to say something!
ううつ !
え!? あ… ぁなんで…
Why?
幽霊でも見たような顔ですね
You look as if you've seen a ghost.
お前は… 死んだはずじや…
You are supposed to be dead!
チツクさん ! チツクさん !
Mr. Chic, Mr. Chic!
は一い どうしたんですか一
ラツクさん
Yeees, what's wrong, Mr. Luck?
もうー人 頼みますよ
Take care of one more for me.
Understood.
分かりました一
But the previous person hasn't had his blood and grease cleaned off yet.
けど前の人の血も油も
落としてないんです
That's why I think it's going to be veeeery painful.
だからア ものすご一く
痛いと思います
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
Wait please!
ま 待つてくれ!
何でも話す! 話すから!
あの変態だけは勘弁してくれぇ !
I'll tell you everything!
Everything!
So don't hand me over to that freak, please!
誰ですか 私を蜂の巣にした奴は
Who is the one who turned me into a beehive?
3ーー
ラック
くラック) おっ
Luck.
フイ一ロ
Firo.
It's creepy when you smirk like that.
二ヤ二ヤしやがつて気味ゎ り い な
何読んでんだ?
What are you reading?
~毒妥しめ魂は知るだろう
己が孤独であることを
"Thy soul shall find itself alone
'mid dark thoughts of the grey tombstone;
鈍色の墓石のごとき暗い思念に
取りつかれ
not one, of all the crowd, to pry
あらゆる群集のうちの
誰 ー 人と して
汝の秘められた時を
探ろうとする者はいない
into thine hour of secrecy..."
昔は この詩力ヾ'ー布くて仕方なかつ た
I was scared to death of this poem when I was young.
But it's different now.
でも 今はそうでもあ り ません
ー年前の あの事件以来…
Ever since that incident a year ago...
どうしてだ?
Why is that?
恐れる必要がなくなつ た分
It seems my nervosity has disappeared as much as the need to fear.
緊張感もなくなつたって
とこでしようか…
死に対するね
Towards death, that is.
へえ‥
You don't think about it?
フイ一口は
何とも思わないんですか?
Nope.
忘れて下さい
Please forget what I said.
そり やそうと…
Anyway, strange people have been wandering on our turf.
最近うちのシマにも
妙な連中カヾうろついてる
Must be some spirited folk from Runorata.
どうせ 丿しノラ一夕の
息のかかつた連中でしょう
When push comes to shove, I'll help you any time.
いざつて時は
いつでも助太刀するぜ
Firo, please pretend you don't know.
フイ一ロ 知らぬ振りをして下さい
これはうちの問題です
It is our problem.
水くさいこと言うんだな
Don't be so cold.
We can't cause problems for the Martillos.
マルテイ一ジヨに
迷惑はかけられません
No need to worry.
心配は無用
ヴイ一ノを呼んであります
I've called upon Vino.
なつ ヴイ一ノ…
Vino?
クレアが来るのか?
Claire is coming over?
He'll arrive with the Flying Pussyfoot tomorrow.
明日のフライングプッシ一フツ 卜号で
到着です
それならアイザックとミリアも
同じ列車だ
Isaac and Miria are on the same train then.
I heard an old friend of Mr. Maiza is riding on it as well.
マイ ザ一さんの古い友達も
乗つてるつて
Let's pick them up together, then.
じやあ 一緒に出迎えに…
Are you sure?
間違いないのか
はい 損傷が激しいですが
Yes...
His injuries are very bad, but...
フライングプツシ一フッ 卜号の
乗客と見て 間違いありません
he was definitely a passenger aboard the Flying Pussyfoot.
何体目になる?
How many bodies does this make?
発見されているだけで十数体
We've discovered over ten so far.
They have been abandoned over a range of multiple kilometers along the track.
線路沿いに数十キロに渡って
点々と遺棄されておりまして…
捜査官殿
一体 何がおったのですか?
Mr. Inspector!
What in the hell has happened here?
極秘事項でね
It's top secret, so...
知らずにおいたほうがいい
It's best you didn't know.
やはり乗つていたらしい
It seems he was aboard after all.
不死者… ですか
An Immortal, you mean?
Yea...
His name was on the passenger list at Chicago station.
シ力ゴ駅の乗客名簿に
名前があったそうだ
その人物の安否は?
What is the status on that person's safety?
That's what we're supposed to find out right now.
それをこれから調べろとの仰せだよ
An incident this big...
これだけの事件
隠しおおせるものかね
I wonder if we can keep it hidden?
サ りバン捜査官
くサ りバン) ん ?
Inspector Sullivan!
What?
何だ?
転落した乗客に
生存者がいたようです
It seems there are survivors among the people who fell from the train.
What?!
何?
うがあ !
ラ ラツクさん
Mr. Luck!
Hey, you all right?
やあ ケガはありませんか?
ああ あ あんた…
さつき確かに撃たれて
Y-Y-You were definitely shot just now...
問題~ ない… ですよね ?
There's no... problem, right?
いて一一っ…って あれ?
Ouch!
Ehh?
痛くないぞ?
It doesn't hurt.
へ‥? れあ !
Isaac!
アイ ザックう ! アイ ザックの傷
キレイになくなってるよ一一!
Your wound has disappeared without a trace!
スグ一手品だな
That's some crazy magic!
次はハ卜が出るかも
A pigeon might just appear next!
What a useless guy.
使えない奴…
You... There's no way you could have lived!
あんた…
まさか 生きてるはずがない
おっ フイ一口…
Firo!
フイ一ロはどこです?
Firo, where are you?
I'm here.
ここだよ
そんな‥
No way!
ふつ んん
At least allow me to do this much.
このぐらいはさせろよな
We'll pay for the damage caused.
損害はうちで持ちます
ですから今日 見たことは…
So... about what you've seen today...
め 減相もない !
Don't be absurd!
あたしや 何も見ませんでしたとも !
I haven't seen a thing!
If I say anything, the best that'll happen
to me is that I'll be sent to an asylum.
第一 こんな話したら
病院送りになんのが関の山で…
However... I don't think we can just ignore this.
しかし… 無視するわけにも
いかないようですね…
I'll find you.
捜してやるさ…
For sure.
必ずな…
I heard that the Flying Pussyfoot is quite a strange train.
フライングプッシ一フツ卜ってのは
かなり変わった列車らしいな
一度見たことがありますが
なんと言うか装飾過多で
I've seen it once, but it looks to be some sort of decorative-type.
If I had to say something about it, it's an antique of bad taste.
どちらかと言うと
悪趣味な代物ですよ
ますます見てえ…
I want to see it more and more.
That's a pity.
残念でしたね…
There was an announcement just now that
フライングプツシ一フッ 卜号は
車両卜ラブルで
the Flying Pussyfoot had some mechanical trouble, so the passenger cars were switched for flatcars...
客車ごと代車に切り替えたって
さっきアナウンスが…
スス マジで!?
For real?!
Anyway, before entering Manhattan,
いずれにせよ
マンハッ夕ンに入る前に
the front car will be switched with an electric car,
先頭車両は煤煙のない電気機関車に
すげ替えられてしまいますから
完全な姿では拝めませんよ
so you won't be able to see all of it.
That might be so...
そうですけど…
Ah, now that I think of it, what kind of person is that old friend of yours, Mr. Maiza?
ああ ところで その古いお友達つて
どういう方なんですか?
マイザ一さん
そうですね…
Yes...
寂しカヾりやのくせに
何でも自分ー人で背負おうとする…
Even though he likes to be on his own,
he tries to carry all the burdens by himself.
そんな夕イブの人でしようか
A person like that, I guess.
常人なら
長生きできない夕イプですね
The type that wouldn't live long, were he an ordinary person, eh?
クレアも逆の意味で
同じようなもんだ
Then Claire would be on the opposite side of the spectrum.
He's bright but way too selfish.
あいつは明るいが我が強すきる
確かに
You're right about that.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
見物するのか捕らえるのか
はつきりしてくれねぇか
You gonna watch me or arrest me?
Make it clear!
俺は こう見えても
かなり機嫌が悪いんだからよォ
Even though I look like this, I'm not in a very good mood!
ル一ア…
こんなことなら
If I knew things were going to turn out like this,
I should've killed you earlier.
もつと早くお前のこと
殺してあげときゃよかつたぜ…
Or... Shall I kill you right here?
それとも… 今 ここで
殺してやろうか?
But... What...
でも… ラツ ド
What's wrong?
何だよ… こ一んな俺に殺されるのは
イヤつてか?
You're saying you don't want to be killed by me?!
うれあ
It hurts, it hurts!
い い 痛い痛い…
ちよっと待ってえ…
Wait a bit!
ごめんよ 二一ス
I'm sorry Nice, but I beg of you!
でも お願いだから もうちよつと
ゆつくりいい~
Walk a little slower.
おい
Hey!
お… お一一い!
お一一い!
Hey!
おお!
工二スにフイ一ロにマイザ一!
Oh! Ennis, Firo and Maiza!
It's been a long time, my good people!
久しぶりだな マイ いい人たち!
元気そうで何よ り だね !
I'm glad you're all healthy!
You and Mr. Isaac, too!
アイザツクさんと三りアさんも
元気 元気!
What happened? You look like shit—
どうしたんだよ
そんなボロボロにな… ウプ!
長い人生 そのうち話す時も来るさア !
痛つ 痛い
If you live long enough, I'll tell you sometime!
おっはつはつは一
久しぶりだな一 おい
It sure has been a long time!
dokomade mo tsuzuiteru hoshizora miagete utau
I sing, looking up into the endless starry night.
kagiriaru bokutachi no eien wo yume miru melody
A melody in a dream... about our limited eternity.
mune ni afureru itoshisa no mizu wa
This water of love, overflowing from my chest...
mirai no hate de dareka ni todoku darou
I wonder if it will reach someone in the future?
shinjite iruyo
I will believe in you.
harukana toki wo kake nukete
Transcending generations of time...
bokutachi no yobigoe wa itsuka ookina uta ni naru
Will our calls turn into a beautiful song one day?
ai wo tsumuide yukeru yo
You can start building your love,
ima wa mada konnani chiisana hikari dakedo
Though right now, the light is still faint.
Next ep
Preview
Setting the Old Woman's
Qualms Aside, the Flying Pussyfoot Departs
Hey Miria, I wonder where that "other place" is.
It means it's not at "home", right?
Then that means it's "somewhere", not "home", right?
Then where is that "somewhere"?
It must be the "somewhere" of the uncertainty of an old woman!
You're amazing, Isaac!